{
    "ronald": [{
        "question": "Chairman Weissman, thanks for taking the time to speak with me today.  I know you have had a big role in the success of Inter-City Opera, but it also seems that the company is at a crossroads.  I’m wondering where you think your best intentions might fall short of achieving a clear path forward for the company?",
        "answer": ["Well, that depends on what we really want, doesn’t it?  Look, I’ve been the CEO of a major corporation for the past two decades.  I have a little bit of experience in this arena.  And the thing is, what the Artistic Director wants to do is just different than what audiences really want.  I mean, my friends, they go to the opera—they want to hear the arias that they know.  That’s just human nature to want familiarity.  They don’t go to be challenged, they don’t go to listen to any of that modern stuff, they want to hear the greatest hits. So if we want to be successful, we have to produce the greatest hits."]
    }, {
        "question": "But isn’t the argument that not everyone wants to hear that music, or feels it is relevant to their lives?  Isn’t there some middle ground?",
        "answer": ["Let me give you a concrete example.  We had 65% sales on our last show that was non-mainstream.  I think it was a Benjamin Britten opera.  And that’s not even that radical.  65%.  That means that more than one in three seats was empty.  We need that money coming in. I mean, earned revenue doesn’t pay for the outgoing costs alone but it’s an important part. "]
    }, {
        "question": "Why do you think that you were not successful filling the house, despite your best efforts?",
        "answer": ["I think it was about the repertoire, and maybe the marketing approach.  You need top-notch marketing if it’s a product that doesn’t have any name recognition.  That’s what we did when we introduced our new product line at KJR—we invested in marketing, and it really paid off."]
    }, {
        "question": "Have you seen any specific trends in the last few years, in terms of audience participation?",
        "answer": ["I don’t have the statistics off the top of my head, but I know when I went to that Fireflight opera, there definitely were more young people around.  It didn’t feel like the typical opera-going crowd.  But they didn’t come to the other shows, so we must have done something wrong.  My friends, they give a lot of money to the opera.  They do that because I give a lot to their charities—you know how it goes.  But they don’t want to see shows like that.  And we need those donations to keep the doors open.  We can’t alienate those people."]
    }, {
        "question": "How might you build support for a new season that brings in both old and young, traditional and non-traditional audiences?  Do you see any beliefs or assumptions that need to be challenged?",
        "answer": ["My wife, she says she doesn’t like it when the young people come wearing jeans and t-shirts to the opera, and she went to the trouble to dress up.  Young people need to learn how to dress and how to act at the opera.  They also always pull out their phones, and sometimes get up and leave before the show is over.  They just need to learn common decent etiquette."]
    }, {
        "question": "So, if I can paraphrase where you are coming from, a lot of new audiences don’t understand the culture of opera-going.  They don’t get the unspoken rules about attending the opera.",
        "answer": ["Yes, that’s right.  Don’t get me started on applause in the middle of a da capo aria."]
    }, {
        "question": "I’m curious what you see as the future of opera, if you don’t like having inexperienced audience members in attendance?",
        "answer": ["That’s my wife’s perspective, not mine so much.  I think we have to get the kids involved.  You know, teach them like I was taught.  My dad used to play the Texaco Metropolitan Opera radio broadcasts in our house on Saturday afternoons.  He’d tell me the stories of the great operas.  Those were some good times, me and him, listening to the radio."]
    }, {
        "question": "So how does educational programming fit into the audience development strategy at Inter-City Opera?",
        "answer": ["You know, we bus in the kids—we bussed in 500 school kids last year to a matinee.  Boy, was that loud!  But it was good.  We need to do more of that. Just don’t invite my wife. Or bring headphones. (laughs)"]
    }, {
        "question": "So if I might summarize, it seems like reaching new audiences needs to be prioritized in order to develop life-long supporters of opera, and also young audiences need to feel welcome to come, even if they are different than the traditional audiences.  But traditional audiences need to feel the art form is respected, and people understand concert culture.  It seems like there is a feedback loop forming here.",
        "answer": ["You must be referring to Peter Senge and systems thinking.  Yeah, we read him back in the ‘80s when I was learning management theory.  I see where you are going with that. (laughs)"]
    }, {
        "question": "Thanks for your time, Mr. Weissman.  I look forward to sharing my analysis with you when I have concluded the other interviews."
    }],
    "gwyneth": [{
        "question": "Hello, Ms. Pendleton.",
        "answer": ["Please call me Gwyneth."]
    }, {
        "question": "All right, Gwyneth.  I was given your name from the Subscription Department at Inter-City Operas as a long-time attendee.  We’re talking to people involved in the company and audience members, to find out what we can do to increase visibility and interest in opera here in Greensboro.  Are you willing to answer a few questions?",
        "answer": ["Sure, I’m all ears. "]
    }, {
        "question": "Great.  I’m curious where your interest in opera comes from.",
        "answer": ["Sure.  You know, I think I saw some operas on PBS growing up, and then we had some artists come to our school at one point, and then we went to a few productions.  I always like the sound of the unamplified voice—so powerful!  It made the hairs on my arms stand up!  In college I founded an Opera Fan Club. I realize that makes me sound like a bit of a nerd!  We would go see the live broadcasts at the Regal Cinemas from the MET—it was about once a month as I recall.  It was actually very fun and lots of new people got involved.  We would share snacks and popcorn.  I loved the interviews in intermission."]
    }, {
        "question": "So as an avid opera-lover, what do you think Inter-City Opera is doing well, and why are they still not successful despite their best efforts?",
        "answer": ["Well, I don’t know what happens on the inside, although I do have a friend in the chorus who says that the Artistic Director is pretty frustrated with the Board, but it seems to me that the programming is pretty conservative.  I mean, if you can see <i>Aida</i> in a broadcast from the MET with, you know, live elephants or whatever, it’s not so appealing to see it in a 600-seat theater.  I really think smaller companies should focus on non-traditional repertoire, experimental productions, and co-productions with theater groups, things like that.  That’s what I miss about living in a smaller city—all the experimental work that you see in places like New York."]
    }, {
        "question": "You work in youth services. Is that correct?",
        "answer": ["Yes, I’m the Operations Manager at the Boys and Girls Club.  We serve underprivileged youth with after-school care five days a week in four club locations across the city."]
    }, {
        "question": "I’m curious what you think about bringing students to the opera.  Do you think that that is answer for creating greater audience participation?",
        "answer": ["Well, of course I’m all for educational programs in the arts.  I think you need to look at your motivations, though.  At the Boys and Girls Club we serve children growing up in poverty in Greensboro, for the most part.  Exposing them to the arts is part of our mission, so I’m all for that.  It’s just that it’s wrong-headed to think of getting kids to love opera, like I did, just so they can buy tickets in the future. I’m not sure that will ever be part of what most of my kids do. It has to be part of the mission of the company to increase access and education, not just try to convert ticket-buyers.  That just feels wrong to me."]
    }, {
        "question": "What assumptions do you see in place culturally that might be causing some of these problems?",
        "answer": ["I’m not sure I feel comfortable going on the record about this, but you know, when we take our kids on field trips to the museum, parks, etc., I do see how people look at us.  Not everyone wants children involved in cultural activities.  They might say they do, but you know, they also want to keep things the way they were—comfortable, safe, white.  It’s hard to talk about, but there are a lot of assumptions about who should have access to culture in our society.  And you have to look at who is paying the bills.  But my kids, they are open to anything—opera, hockey, whatever!  I mean, get them while they are young. That’s what I say."]
    }, {
        "question": "Gwyneth, this conversation has been very enlightening.  Thanks for all that you do.",
        "answer": ["Of course!  See you at the opera!"]
    }],
    "jose": [{
        "question": "Mr. Ruiz, would you mind talking to me for a few moments?",
        "answer": ["Of course. What can I do you for?"]
    }, {
        "question": "I’m collecting information regarding an audience interest in the work of Inter-City Opera. Are you familiar with the company?",
        "answer": ["Not really.  Aren’t they the opera company in town?"]
    }, {
        "question": "Yes.  So it’s safe to assume you haven’t seen a production?",
        "answer": ["Opera?  No. Not my thing.  I’m more into sports, you know?  Plus, isn’t opera really expensive?"]
    }, {
        "question": "Well, actually, tickets start at $25 so it depends on what you typically spend on entertainment.  What would get you in the door to the opera?",
        "answer": ["I guess if my wife wanted me to go . . . Just kidding. But all that screaming, you know, like (demonstrates operatic sound).  And it’s in another language—German or Italian, right?  You know, come to think about it, I did hear about the one show they did—<i>Fireflight</i>.  My colleague at work was all excited, and a bunch of people went together.  They were talking about it the next day.  I heard it was crazy.  I just didn’t put it together until now."]
    }, {
        "question": "If your colleagues arranged a group visit, do you think you would go next time?",
        "answer": ["Well, now that we have had this talk, it’s going to be more familiar to me. So maybe.  I don’t know.  Maybe I could get my wife tickets for her birthday.  I mean, I’m open to new experiences.  I’m not dead yet! (laughs)"]
    }, {
        "question": "Thanks for talking with me!",
        "answer": ["Sure."]
    }],
    "delia": [{
        "question": "Hi Ms. Phillips, do you have some time to talk about Inter-City Opera?",
        "answer": ["Um . . . sure, I guess so.  I’ve worked for them a few times."]
    }, {
        "question": "As a soloist, right?",
        "answer": ["Yes. They hire out their principal roles to people from New York, but I’ve done some small roles and understudies."]
    }, {
        "question": "OK. So I’m looking into audience development strategies on everything from programming choices to educational programs.  What was your experience like at the company?  What do you think is holding them back despite their best efforts?",
        "answer": ["You know, I have to be really careful what I say, because I want to work for them again!  Is this off the record?"]
    }, {
        "question": "Yes, I won’t use your name.",
        "answer": ["OK. Well, it seems like cash flow is a real issue.  One time we didn’t get our checks until a month after the production closed.  I heard that Ron Weissman had to bail them out.  But you didn’t hear that from me."]
    }, {
        "question": "Got it.  Cash flow issues.  What about community support and perception?",
        "answer": ["If you talk to certain people in Greensboro, they know all about what they are doing, but the average person doesn’t have a clue.  They think opera is this dead art form.  We have to do cutting-edge work to keep it alive.  I’m even thinking of starting my own company so I can do more innovative work—and sing the lead role every time! Just kidding about that last part.  But yeah, artists have to make their own work these days.  There just isn’t enough work to go around, even if you did get a great gig. There are a lot of great singers in Greensboro because the university is so into opera. So it’s tough to get work."]
    }, {
        "question": "Are there any ways that the university can work with the companies so help create more demand?  Do you see the stakeholders communicating?",
        "answer": ["Everyone knows everyone.  There’s a lot of overlap.  It’s in the university’s best interest to train more and more great singers, but then the city can’t sustain them all.  That’s why I’m thinking about moving to Boston or New York.  It’s just so expensive there.  That’s why I’m still here!"]
    }, {
        "question": "That sheds some light on the employment factors at the company and the supply and demand of the labor.  I appreciate your time.",
        "answer": ["Sure!  And remember, hush-hush, right?"]
    }, {
        "question": "You got it."
    }],
    "woodruff": [{
        "question": "So nice to meet with you, Mrs.  Woodruff, Ms. Smith",
        "answer": [
            "(Woodruff) Please call me Bitsy.  Everyone else does.",
            "(Smith) And I go by Genny."
        ]
    }, {
        "question": "Great! Again thanks to both of you.",
        "answer": [
            "(Woodruff) So why did you pull me away from my garden club meeting today?  That’s just a little joke, dear."
        ]
    }, {
        "question": "I’m conducting some conversations around the future of Inter-City Opera. As a prominent board member, Bitsy, and Genny, as the Development Director, I thought you might have some valuable insight into how we got to the place we are now, and where we might go forward from here.",
        "answer": [
            "(Woodruff) I see. Well, I’ve said it before and I’ll say it again loud and clear—that <i>Fireflight</i> opera last year was an absolute disaster.  My friends were talking about it for weeks. I was so embarrassed.  Ron had to talk me down before I came to the next board meeting.  And the thing is, my friends buy tables at the gala every year to the tune of $5,000 each. So it was no small matter. ",
            "(Smith) Bitsy is right. It was hard to sell gala tables this past year.  Some of the corporations backed out too, and we really need their support.  People just felt the opera was going in a direction that they were not comfortable supporting.",
            "(Woodruff) And the Artistic Director. We had tea recently and talked this through.  The vision, the vision. . . .  I have made myself very clear.  I cannot support this type of nonsense in the future.  It is an opera company, for god’s sake, not a cabaret, or whatever that was."
        ]
    }, {
        "question": "So what do you say to sold out ticket sales for <i>Fireflight</i>?",
        "answer": [
            "(Woodruff) Well, I don’t know who was buying those tickets.  Certainly my friends didn’t like it one bit, and they didn’t recommend it to their friends.",
            "(Smith) One challenge we face on the fundraising front is that single-ticket buyers, like the ones who came out for <i>Fireflight</i>, are not likely to give donations to the opera.  We’re not even sure if they are going to come back!  If we alienate our angels like Bitsy, well, then we’re all in trouble."
        ]
    }, {
        "question": "I see. . . .  So, can you imagine a mix of programming that would appeal to many different people?  Or is that not appropriate in your opinion?",
        "answer": [
            "(Woodruff) You know, I restore historic homes.  Well, I don’t do it myself. I advise.  Anyway, when the new fixtures come in, and it’s all a mishmash, it can just look . . . provincial, nouveau riche.  That’s how I think about these modern operas.  They ruin a perfectly beautiful art form.  Now if you don’t mind, I’m going to slip out.  It has been an absolute pleasure.  Make sure you take down my opinion in that tape recorder of yours."
        ]
    }, {
        "question": "I’ve got every word. Thank you both for your time.  Ginny, can I talk with you another moment?",
        "answer": [
            "(Smith) Certainly.  (Woodruff leaves.) You see what I’m dealing with.  These are the conversations I have every day.  I had to travel to Fort Lauderdale a few weeks ago just to sweet talk one of our major donors after the Artistic Director proposed some new works for next season.  We’ll never raise our budget with this type of nay-saying among the big-wigs."
        ]
    }, {
        "question": "Do you try to convince them to like something they don’t like, or what do you do? ",
        "answer": [
            "(Smith) Personally I like a lot of different styles of music. I used to play new age flute music if you can believe it. But, you know, I placate them and listen to their complaints, and then I try to find positive things to say.  I try to keep them feeling like they are part of the family; like they have influence.  It’s a tough balance."
        ]
    }, {
        "question": "I can see that.  Wow.  I don’t envy you your job.  It’s tough.",
        "answer": [
            "(Smith) Right!"
        ]
    }],
    "joe": [{
        "question": "Mr. Weston, thanks for taking my call.",
        "answer": ["Certainly.  I’ve only got 10 minutes.  On the clock. You know how it is."]
    }, {
        "question": "I understand.  I just want to ask a few questions about Inter-City Opera, and how the success of the company would be good for Greensboro.",
        "answer": ["Greensboro is city with a thriving arts scene.  I’m proud to be a City Council member in this great place.  Best city on the East Coast."]
    }, {
        "question": "OK, but Inter-City Opera has been struggling to meet costs.  What is the value of the arts for your city? What kind of investment does the city make in the arts?"
    }, {
        "answer": ["Let me start with your first question.  The arts are very valuable.  Very valuable.  First of all, they bring people downtown. They eat out, park their cars, have a drink afterwards.  It’s a value-added for our city.  In terms of our investment, they are doing just fine, with the sponsorships they receive from local companies.  Weissman is a heck of a leader, isn’t he?  He has lots of friends in the companies around town. "]
    }, {
        "question": "From your perspective, then, Inter-City Opera is doing well?  They are serving the city and its mission?",
        "answer": ["Well, we like to see innovation here in Greensboro.  Culture attracts people to our city.  They spend money.  It’s also a great place to be seen—the events and so on, I mean.  I fully support them.  Of course, we don’t have any money to put their way directly.  They apply for grants and so on.  Through the Council.  If they don’t get them, someone else will.  Whatever the people want, that’s what’s good for Greensboro."]
    }, {
        "question": "You don’t have a vested interest in keeping opera in Greensboro?",
        "answer": ["It’s not my place to decide, you know?  Whatever the people want, that’s good for us."]
    }, {
        "question": "I see.  Thanks for your time.",
        "answer": ["You bet."]
    }]
}
